allvoices.com 2014-06-27

# Privacy Policy :: allvoices - events, people, places that matter - tell us your news

## Effective Date: August 25, 2011 | Amended April 1, 2013

Allvoices (“Allvoices” or “we”) respects and values your privacy. As such, this Privacy Policy details Allvoices’ treatment of personally identifiable information (“PII”) and other information collected through this website. 

Allvoices reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted on this website and the effective date of the Privacy Policy will be modified to reflect the effective date of the most recent version. If a material change to our information practices occurs in the future, we will only use PII collected from the time of the policy change forward for these new purposes unless we have your consent. 

he terms and conditions governing your use of the Allvoices website are contained in a separate Terms of Use agreement available at <http://www.allvoices.com/terms>.

## Types of Information We Collect or Maintain About Individuals through This Website 

**Personally Identifiable Information**

PII is information that allows Allvoices to identify and communicate with you. 

We have designed the Allvoices website so that you can view the website without providing Allvoices with any PII or having an Allvoices account. This type of user is known as a Visitor.

Certain activities on the Allvoices website, including contribution, report or submission of breaking news; creating a news event; sharing videos, news, URLs, images or perspectives; asking a question; answering a question; commenting; creating a user profile; or sharing website content with a friend via email, SMS or MMS require you to create an account with Allvoices. This type of user is known as a Registered User. To create an account, you must register as a Registered User and Allvoices may collect or maintain the following PII about you:

First and last name; physical address; email address; mobile phone number; gender; age; education; occupation; photographs; personal interests; and any other PII you submit during the course of normal correspondence (including SMS, MMS and email) with Allvoices (collectively “Profile Information”).

We may combine this PII with information from other sources. By creating an account and providing Allvoices your mobile phone number, you expressly agree that Allvoices may contact you by SMS (i.e. “text”) message or Multimedia Messaging Service (MMS). If you send information to Allvoices via SMS or MMS, Allvoices may respond to you via SMS or MMS.

## Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Non-personally identifiable information is information Allvoices collects in the normal course of operating the Allvoices website that does not reveal the specific identity of the individual. We collect certain aggregate and non-personal information when you visit this website. This information does not relate to a single identifiable visitor. 

When you visit the website to browse, read or download information, we automatically collect standard computer information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring website addresses. We generally do not link standard computer information to anything that will allow us to identify users unless to enforce compliance with our rules or terms of service or to protect our service, site, users or others. 

We also may collect aggregate and non-personal information through "Cookies" or other website technology as explained below. 

## How We Use PII Collected on the Allvoices Website

**Individual PII Collected on the Allvoices Website**

Allvoices is intended to be a global community for discussion around news, events and people. Accordingly, the Allvoices website publicly displays some Profile Information, including a Registered User’s pictures, name, username and location (country and city) to facilitate user interaction on the Allvoices website. 

We use Registered User’s email addresses to share content and to notify you of important updates to the Privacy Policy or Terms of Use. We do not share with, or display to, other website users a Registered User’s email address or mobile phone number. To facilitate searching and finding friends and acquaintances on the Allvoices website, Allvoices allows users to search for other Registered Users based on location (country and city) and interests. Registered Users may email other Registered User’s through the Allvoices website without obtaining the recipient’s email address. We recognize and highlight our Registered Users (user names) on Registered User Reports and search pages accessed through search terms based on location and key interests/contributions.

We may also use a Registered User’s email address or mobile phone number to send email, SMS and MMS updates or news, such as an email newsletter, regarding the Allvoices website or other services and products that may be of interest to Registered Users. 

We may create anonymous records from PII by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the information personally identifiable to you. We may use this anonymous information to analyze request and usage patterns to improve the website and our services. We reserve the right to use and disclose this anonymous information to third parties for various purposes, including for internal business analysis and to provide aggregate demographic data to our partners.

Registered Users can invite friends to join the Allvoices website by sending invitation emails and by using our automated invitation system. Allvoices stores the email addresses that Registered Users provide so that the respondents may be added to the sender’s friends’ list. We may also send up to 3 reminders of the invitations (via email only). Allvoices does not sell these email addresses. 

Users can also login to the Allvoices website using their Facebook or Twitter username and password through Facebook Connect or Sign in with Twitter or such other services as we may make available for login from time to time. Information provided to Facebook or Twitter will be subject to those entities’ respective privacy policies. Once a user logs in with a Facebook or Twitter username and password, certain PII will be shared with Allvoices. We will treat this shared information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Sharing of Individual PII with Third Parties

Allvoices will not sell, rent or lease PII collected on the Allvoices website to third-party marketers. Allvoices, may however, share PII with its affiliates (Allvoices is a subsidiary of PulsePoint) who may use the information for marketing purposes. For more information, please see the PulsePoint [Privacy Policy](http://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy/). Our affiliates will not share PII with unaffiliated third parties for their own marketing purposes.

Allvoices may share PII with service providers who assist us with our marketing efforts and other communications, but those service providers will not use this PII for their own marketing purposes and are prohibited by contract from sharing this PII with any party other than Allvoices. These businesses include providers of website applications. These services enable us to deliver communications to website users and to verify and update information about website users.

Allvoices may also share PII in the following limited circumstances: (1) upon receipt of a properly authorized and authenticated governmental request for information; (2) in response to a subpoena or a court order; (3) to comply with relevant laws; (4) in response to an investigation of fraud regarding a specific individual; (5) in an effort to safeguard the person or property of an Allvoices employee or a third party; or (6) when Allvoices believes it is necessary to protect our interests or we believe in good faith that the law requires the sharing of your PII. 

Finally, Allvoices may, in the future, decide to sell, merge or otherwise reorganize its business. Allvoices reserves the right to transfer and disclose PII in this circumstance, but data collected by Allvoices will be governed by the same privacy policy that existed prior to any change in business conditions unless you consent to the new privacy policy.

## How We Use Non-Personally Identifiable Information Collected on the Allvoices Website

We use non-personally identifiable information to help us to tailor the features, performance and support of our products and services to website users; to offer you additional information and opportunities; and to inform you of changes to this Privacy Policy the Terms of Use of the website. The non-personally identifiable information we collect may be shared with Allvoices’ affiliates and third parties to provide you with more relevant services and advertisements to website users, including advertisements relating to Allvoices on other websites you may visit.

**How We Use Cookies on the Allvoices Website**

Cookies are pieces of information that any website may transfer to your browser that are then stored in your computer's system. Cookies are returned to the website that deposited them when a visitor returns to that site. We use Cookies to store users’ preferences and to record session information. We also use Cookies for purposes including ensuring that users are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements and to customize newsletter, advertising and web page content based on browser type and user profile information. The deposit of Cookies by the website may enhance your online experience by allowing us to save your preferences for your next visit. Our Cookies may also measure the general activity on the website and measure advertising effectiveness, which allows us to determine which areas and features are most popular. This information allows us to make improvements to our website.

Most web browsers are set up to accept cookies. You can, however, reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. If you choose to decline Cookies, some of the functionality of the website may be impaired. Some of the cookies placed may be from our affiliate PulsePoint’s Audience business. For more information, please see the PulsePoint Audience [privacy policy](http://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy/audience-business-privacy/). Should you wish to opt-out of us placing an Audience audience cookie on your browser, you can click [here](http://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy/optout/) to deploy an "opt-out" cookie on your browser. This cookie, when installed on your browser, will prevent us from placing a new Audience audience cookie on that browser and will prevent the Audience audience business from collecting web data and audience data on that browser. 

Web beacons, also known as "clear gifs," "one-pixel gifs," "web bugs," "Internet tags" or "pixel tags," are small graphic images on a website or in an email that allow us and third parties to monitor the activity on our website or to make Cookies more effective. We use log files to store the data that is collected through web beacons.

**Third Party Advertising**

Ads appearing on the Allvoices website may be delivered to you by Allvoices or its affiliates or by one of Allvoices’ web advertising partners or advertising networks. Allvoices may allow third-party advertisers or advertising networks that will present advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their Cookies on your computer. These Cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisement that they believe will be of most interest to you. Advertisers’ use of Cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this Privacy Policy.

The Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), a self-regulatory organization consisting of online advertising networks, has an opt-out tool that allows you to opt out of the data collection and targeted ad programs of NAI members. You may access the NAI opt-out tool here. PrivacyChoice's opt-out tool allows you to opt out of other third parties (in addition to NAI members) who may place cookies on your computer. To opt out of these third parties, please go to [http://www.privacychoice.org/choose.](http://www.privacychoice.org/choose)

## Choice

Allvoices Registered Users may modify or remove any of their PII at any time by logging into their account and accessing features such as “Edit Profile” and “Account Information.” 

Registered Users may also control the types of messages they receive by changing settings through the “Edit Profile” feature. U.S. Registered Users can opt out of SMS messages using the “Edit Profile” feature or by sending STOP or END or CANCEL or UNSUBSCRIBE or STOP ALL from your mobile device to VOICES (864237). Please note that this will only work if you have previously submitted content using the same mobile number and are in the Allvoices system.

Recipients of invitations from Allvoices may contact Allvoices using the contact information below under “Access” to request removal of their information from our database.

## Security

We endeavor to safeguard and protect our users' information. When users submit information on our website, such information is protected both online and offline. The servers in which we store PII are kept in a secure physical environment. Allvoices has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under our control. Please be advised that, although we take reasonable technological precautions to protect your data, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, Allvoices cannot warrant that your information will be absolutely secure. Any transmission of data at or through our website is at your own risk. However, access to your information is strictly limited, and not accessible to the public.

## Children's Privacy

Allvoices places the highest value on the privacy of children. Allvoices does not knowingly collect PII from children under the age of 13.

**Access**

Individuals wishing to review PII collected by Allvoices on this website should write to Allvoices’ Privacy Department, c/o PulsePoint, 20 Broad Street, 6th Floor, New York, NY 10014. Allvoices may take reasonable steps to confirm the identity of the consumer in an effort to prevent identity theft.

## European Union and Other Non-US Residents

Your information may be stored and processed in any country in which Allvoices or its affiliates maintain facilities, including in the United States, which may not have protections equivalent to those in your home country. For purpose of providing the service or sharing or disclosing data for purposes noted in this policy, Allvoices reserves the right to transfer information outside of your country. By using and registering on the Allvoices website, you consent to the transfer of information outside of your country.

In addition, Allvoices’ parent company, PulsePoint, has self-certified to the Department of Commerce's Safe-Harbor framework, and we adhere to the Safe-Harbor Principles. For more information on the Safe-Harbor program, visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor>. If you are a European resident and have a data-privacy inquiry, you may contact us at [info@pulsepoint.com](mailto:info@pulsepoint.com) or in writing at:

PulsePoint  
20 Broad Street, 6th Floor  
New York, NY 10014  
Tel: (212) 706-9781

If your data privacy inquiry was not satisfactorily resolved by us then you may contact the DMA Safe Harbor Program at:

Safe Harbor Line Direct Marketing Association  
1615 L Street, NW - Suite 1100  
Washington, DC 20036  
Fax: 202-955-0085  
Telephone: 202-861-2410  
Email: [safeharbor@the-dma.org ](mailto:safeharbor@the-dma.org)

## Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who have provided PII to PulsePoint or its partners to request certain information regarding Allvoices disclosure of PII to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Within thirty days of receiving such a request, we will provide a list of the categories of PII disclosed to third parties for third-party direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the names and addresses of the third parties when required. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified in this section.

If you have any questions about your California privacy rights or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@allvoices.com](mailto:privacy@allvoices.com) or in writing at:

Allvoices Privacy Department  
c/o PulsePoint  
20 Broad Street, 6th Floor  
New York, NY 10014  
Tel: (212) 706-9781
